{"tossups": [{"question": "Chairman Howard Smith tried to stop the passage of this act, which was lobbied for by Joseph Rauh and Clarence Mitchell. Barry Goldwater opposed this bill saying, \u201cyou can\u2019t legislate morality\u201d, while the president in office during this bill\u2019s passage noted that \u201cwe might lose the South, but those sorts of states may be lost anyway\u201d. Ardent segregationist Robert Byrd filibustered this bill. Lyndon Johnson passed, for ten points, what act that barred racial discrimination in public areas such as schools?", "answer": "1964<b> Civil Rights</b> Act", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Regions on the boundaries of these areas were called purlieu. Henry III reformed laws in these areas via a 1217 Charter that gave free men access to them after they had been established by William the Conqueror as outside of common law. The Dean one of these places was a source of charcoal and the New one was a habitat for many animals. The Sherwood one of these locations was where Robin Hood supposed hid at Major Oak. For ten points, name these wooded areas that were once where Norman Kings could hunt deer.", "answer": "Royal<b> Forest</b> (or<b> Kingswood</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "4 mile long Rafael Urdaneta Bridge services this body of water. Lightning storms are common where this body of water meets the Catatumbo River. The explorer Alonso de Ojeda became the first European to see this body of water, where he noticed natives living on stilt houses. 18% of this body of water is victim to a duckweed infestation. For ten points, identify this large tidal estuary, sometimes called a lake, on Venezuela\u2019s northern coast.", "answer": "Lake<b> Maracaibo</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This battle inspired the legend of lieutenants Coghill and Melvill, who had nearly escaped to safety carrying the Queen\u2019s standard. A solar eclipse rose over this battle during the final stand of Anthony Durnford. Garnet Wolseley was ordered to replace Lord Chelmsford after this battle. After an ultimatum from Bartle Frere expired, the losing side in this battle crossed the Buffalo River only to be overrun by the enemy<em> impi</em>. For ten points, identify this opening battle of the Anglo-Zulu war, a defeat for Great Britain.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Isandlwana</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A Republican Senator running for re-election in this state was widely criticized for calling an Indian man \u201cmacaca\u201d in 2006. A random drawing for a state delegate seat in this state in 2017 was lost by Democrat Shelly Simonds. Ken Cuccinelli and Ed Gillespie were failed gubernatorial candidates in this state. Recent sexual assault allegations and blackface incidents have plagued this state\u2019s top 3 Democratic leaders. For 10 points, name this mid-Atlantic state led by embattled governor Ralph Northam.", "answer": "<b> Virginia</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<em>Note: country and branch of military required.</em> Mason Patrick served as this branch\u2019s first commander. This branch redeemed its failure in the Shasta disaster with a successful attack on the Rex. George Kenney pioneered a \u201cskip\u201d technique used by this branch. The sinking of the<em> Ostfriedland</em> by this branch was led by Billy Mitchell, who argued that its forces should be used to sink battleships. This branch\u2019s military academy is located in Colorado Springs. Eddie Rickenbacker and Curtis LeMay belonged to, for ten points, what branch of the U.S. military?", "answer": "<b> U.S. Air Force</b> (accept<b> USAF</b>; prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This word was defined in the first meeting of the United Nations General Assembly by its Resolution 96. A definition of this word in one convention excluded this word\u2019s application to politics due to the USSR\u2019s protests. That convention includes the \u201cin whole or in part\u201d and the \u201cintent to destroy\u201d phrases. This word was originally coined in response to an Armenian instance of it. \u201cNational, ethnic, racial, or religious groups\u201d can be targeted by, for ten points, what crime exemplified by the Holocaust?", "answer": "<b> \u201cgenocide\u201d</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Misiginubik are horned versions of these animals in unending conflict with Algonquin thunderbirds. The Adena culture built a quarter-mile mound in the shape of one of these animals, also present on the emblem of the Mayan city of Calakmul. The main pyramid of Chichen Itza is dedicated to a flying one of these animals responsible for bringing rain. That deity is similar to an Aztec god depicted as the wind and which had feathers. Quetzalcoatl was depicted as, for ten points, what kind of legless reptile?", "answer": "<b> snake</b> or<b> serpent</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {"question": "Negotiations during this event were carried out by John A. Scali of ABC News and Aleksandr Fomin. Amintore Fanfani offered to withdraw weapons in Apulia in this event, which was conveyed by Ettore Bernabei to Arthur Schlesinger. EXCOMM was alerted in this event that Major Rudolf Anderson had been killed, while during this event\u2019s \u201cBlack Saturday\u201d, the submarine B-59 under Vasily Arkhipov refused to launch a nuclear torpedo. Resolved by removing Jupiter missiles in Turkey, this event began with construction of launch facilities in Cuba. Khruschev and JFK narrowly avoided war in, for ten points, what 1962 crisis?", "answer": "<b> Cuban Missile</b> Crisis or (<b>October Crisis of 1961</b> or<b> Missile Scare</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The salt flats of Gu\u00b4erande are located north of the mouth of this river, whose estuary is located south of Saint-Nazaire. This river joins with its tributary, the Maine, at Angers. Blois and Chambord are among over a thousand chateaux located along this river. Hundreds of priests and counter-revolutionaries were drowned in barges during the War in the Vend\u00b4ee. This river flows through Orleans and Nantes before emptying into the Bay of Biscay. For ten points, name this longest river of France.", "answer": "<b> Loire</b> River", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Juliette Gordon Low, the founder of the Girl Scouts, was born in this city, where the second oldest continuously run hospital, the Candler Hospital, is located. Near this city, Pierce Mease Butler authorized the sale of over 436 slaves in the Weeping Time, in what was possibly the largest sale of slaves in U.S. history. With Haitian recruits, the Comte d\u2019Estaing helped launch a 1779 attack on this city which was then defended by British soldiers under John Maitland. James Oglethorpe developed a plan to build this city located in a colony for debtors. For ten points, name this city on Georgia\u2019s Atlantic Coast.", "answer": "<b> Savannah</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This city was responsible for developing the trireme and fought history\u2019s first recorded naval battle against Cocyra. Lais was one of the<em> hetairas</em> in city\u2019s temple of Aphrodite. This city\u2019s legendary bronze alloy may have been discovered when gold fused with copper when Lucius Mummius burnt this city to the ground. The Bacchiadae originally ruled this city but were overthrown by the tyrant Cypselus and his son Periander. For ten points, identify this Greek city-state located on a namesake Isthmus.", "answer": "<b> Corinth</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "Historian Tyler Dennett was the first to discover an agreement between this country and the U.S. in 1924, which he interpreted as a secret treaty. This country\u2019s \u201cSpecial interests\u201d were acknowledged in an agreement that Robert Lansing signed in 1917 that effectively contradicted the Open Door Policy in China. Elihu Root signed an agreement with a diplomat from this country in 1908 which followed an informal immigration agreement between this country and the U.S. that allowed \u201cpicture brides\u201d to enter America while also ending certain Asian immigration into the United States. President Taft had a memorandum with, for ten points, what country that signed the Treaty of Portsmouth with Russia?", "answer": "<b> Japan</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man\u2019s wife ran over his father-in-law and predecessor with a chariot in the Street of Crime. This man eliminated (+) Turnus Herdonius by planting swords in his home and then accusing him of launching a coup. This man\u2019s final attempt to regain power was thwarted at the battle of Lake Regillus. This man\u2019s forces were held back at the Sublician Bridge by Horatius the One-Eyed despite having earlier allied with (*)</b> Lars Porsena of Clusium. This man was driven from the throne by Lucius Brutus after this man\u2019s son Servius blackmailed and raped Lucretia. Known as \u201cthe Proud,\u201d for ten points, name this final king of Rome.", "answer": "<b> Tarquin the Proud</b> (accept Lucius<b> Tarquinius Superbus</b>, prompt on just Tarquin)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Richard Hamilton assisted in the completion of one of these works, whose primary author was upset that Hamilton was not given credit. Bryan Birch and Peter Swinnerton-Dyer</b> <b>name one of these works relating to the (+)</b> <b>rational solutions of elliptic curves. In 2003,</b> <b>rational solutions of elliptic curves. In 2003,</b> <b>after one of these works was completed, Grigori Perelman declined the (*)</b> <b>after one of these works was completed, Grigori Perelman declined the (*)</b> Clay Institute\u2019s award. P versus NP and the Riemann Hypothesis are among, for ten points, what set of seven problems of modern mathematics that were given a $1 million bounty in the year 2000?", "answer": "<b> Millennium</b> Prize problems", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Participants in this event waved flags with a (+) </b> <b>star cut out from the center. During this event, the \u201cButcher of Barcelona\u201d Erno Gero was removed from power. Cardinal (*) </b> Mindszenty fled to the U.S. after praising participants of this event, who were collectively honored as the Freedom Fighter\u2019s by TIME\u2019s Man of the Year. The executions of Miklos Gimes and Imre Nagy followed, for ten points, what 1956 revolt against Soviet rule that was started in Budapest.", "answer": "<b> Hungarian Revolution</b> of 1956 (accept<b> Soviet invasion</b> of<b> Hungary</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A palace in this city, the Daidairi, was thought to be haunted and suffered from crimes like burglary. Built as a scale model of the city of Chang\u2019an in Tang China, this city was</b> <b>known as the (+)</b> <b>\u201ctranquility and peace capital.\u201d In 1864, this city faced the Hamaguri</b> <b>\u201ctranquility and peace capital.\u201d In 1864, this city faced the Hamaguri</b> <b>Gate Rebellion against the Tokugawa, and in 1950 its Temple of (*)</b> <b>Gate Rebellion against the Tokugawa, and in 1950 its Temple of (*)</b> Golden Pavilion burned down. This city names a protocol to lower greenhouse gas emissions that the U.S. did not sign. Located in Kansai and forming a metropolitan area with Kobe and Osaka, for ten points, name this former imperial capital of Japan.", "answer": "<b> Kyoto</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A Thomas Mann quote prefaces a work by this man declaring \u201cAnd maybe what they say is true / Of war and war\u2019s alarms.\u201d This man mocked his life through a narrator who laments \u201cI must lie down where all the ladders start / In the foul rag and bone shop of the</b> <b>heart\u201d to conclude his poem \u201cThe (+)</b> <b>Circus Animals\u2019 Desertion.\u201d While he mentioned</b> <b>\u201cThose that I fight I do not hate / Those that I guard I do not love,\u201d in a poem eulogizing aviator Robert Gregory, this poet himself died on a (*)</b> \u201ccold dark day,\u201d according to a eulogy titled for him. For ten points, name this man remembered in a W.H. Auden poem, the Irish poet of\u201cEaster, 1916.\u201d", "answer": "William Bulter<b> Yeats</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This work\u2019s accusation of Gustave Flaubert\u2019s short story \u201cHerodias\u201d as contributing to its title phenomenon was criticized by Robert Irwin, who noted Flaubert only spent a brief</b> <b>time in (+)</b> <b>Egypt. This work argues that its title concept creates knowledge contributing</b> <b>to a discourse with uneven power relations and is based in cultural representations made in opposition to a (*)</b> \u201cEuropean identity,\u201d creating an \u201cOther\u201d to implicitly justify imperialism. For ten points, name this foundational work in postcolonial studies about European representations of \u201cThe East\u201d by Edward Said [Sai-EED].", "answer": "<b> Orientalism</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) <b>Further autonomy was granted to this island by the Pact of Halepa, and this</b> <b>island saw the 1905 Theriso Revolt. A British security force was attacked by Muslim</b> <b>irregulars during this island\u2019s (+)</b> <b>Candia massacre, which led to a short state that</b> <b>was ruled by Alexander Zaimis and Eleftherios Venizelos. A civilization on this island</b> <b>was interrupted by the eruption of (*)</b> Thera where ancient palaces had plumbing systems. Arthur Evans studied a culture on this island that included the site of Knossos. The Minoan Civilization was formed on, for ten points, what Greek Island? ANSWER:<b> Crete</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}